Register of the Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria Papers, 1846-1956
Hoover Institution Archives
Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria Papers,
1846-1956
87004
Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, 1861-1948
117 microfilm reels (17.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, relating to Bulgarian foreign relations and domestic policy, the Bulgarian role in the Balkan Wars and World War I, and Bulgarian dynastic affairs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Bulgaria--History--Ferdinand I, 1887-1918.; Bulgaria--Politics and government--1878-1944.; Bulgaria--Court and courtiers.; Balkan Peninsula--History--War of 1912-1913.; World War, 1914-1918--Bulgaria.; World War, 1914-1918--Diplomatic history.; Saxe-Coburg, House of.; Bulgaria.; Balkan Peninsula.; World War, 1914-1918.
Biographical Note
1861, Feb. 26 Born, Vienna, Austria
1879 Author, Itinera Principum S. Coburgi
1887, July 7 Elected prince of Bulgaria
1893, April 20 Married Marie Louise of Bourbon-Parme
1908 Married Eleonore, Princess of Reuss Proclaimed independence of Bulgaria and took the title of czar
1918, Oct. 4 Abdicated in favor of his son, Boris
1948, Sept. 10 Died, Coburg, Germany
Series Description
- CHRONOLOGICAL FILE, 1846-1956 (Boxes 1-88)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter, arranged chronologically and by physical form or subject within each year.
Container List
This collection is only available on microfilm. A guide to reel contents, available at the Hoover Institution Archives reading room, converts the box numbers listed below to microfilm reel numbers.
- CHRONOLOGICAL FILE, 1846-1956
  - Undated
    - General (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - General (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
    - Letters of Imre Kohary (Folder 6)
  - 1846, general (Folder 7)
  - 1848, correspondence (Folder 8)
  - 1859-60, general (Folder 9)
  - 1865, Petenyi, Johann S., a biography (Folder 10)
  - 1879, April, notes by Ferdinand (Folder 11)
  - 1881, general (Folder 12)
  - 1883-86, correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1886-87, correspondence, incoming (Folder 2)
  - 1887
    - General
      - Report on Turkey. Typescript. (Folder 3)
      - III Veliko Narodno Sobranie v Tyrnovo, minutes of meeting at which Ferdinand was elected to Bulgarian throne (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 5)
      - "Arkhiv zu Wien. Auszuge und Dokumente", excerpts from miscellaneous correspondence, mostly diplomatic corps (Folder 6-7)
      - Incoming, congratulatory telegrams sent to Prince Ferdinand upon accession to throne of Bulgaria (Folder 8-14)
      - Outgoing
        - Drafts of letters accepting Bulgarian invitation to the throne (Folder 15)
        - Copies of outgoing correspondence, including letter to Alexander III, Emperor of Russia and Franz-Josef, Emperor of Austria (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Printed matter
      - Clippings from miscellaneous European newspapers (Folder 2-3)
      - Rusko-Turska voina 1877-78 g. Deistviiata na Ruschushkiia otriad, printed copy (Folder 4)
  - 1888, correspondence, "Arkhiv zu Wien. Auszuge und Dokumente", excerpts and summaries of official correspondence (Folder 5)
  - 1889, correspondence, "Arkhiv zu Wien. Auszuge und Dokumente," summaries and transcripts of official correspondence (Folder 6)
  - 1890, correspondence, "Arkhiv zu Wien. Auszuge und Dokumente," summaries and transcripts of official correspondence (Folder 7)
  - 1891
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 9)
      - Summaries and transcripts of official correspondence (Folder 10)
    - Military matters
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Reports, miscellaneous military units (Folder 12)
      - "Skhema Voenno Ministersto" (Folder 13)
      - Sophia Garrison (Folder 14)
    - Printed matter, "Posleden' apel' G.S. Stambolovu", printed leaflet (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Railroads (Folder 2)
    - Vienna Exposition (Folder 3)
  - 1892
    - Agence Balkanique, miscellaneous reports (Folder 4)
    - Clippings (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 6-7)
      - Bourchier, James (Folder 8)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 9)
      - Grekov, D., includes miscellaneous diplomatic correspondence (Folder 10-13)
      - Incoming (Folder 14-16)
      - Outgoing (Folder 17)
      - Regenspurky, O. von (Folder 18)
      - Stambolov, Stefan (Folder 19)
      - Standacher, E.(?) (Folder 20)
      - Summaries and transcripts of official correpondence (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - Zhivkov (Folder 3)
    - Financial reports, including national debt (Folder 4)
    - Marriage to Marie-Louise of Bourbon-Parme (Folder 5)
    - Military matters
      - "Notes sur les fortifications de Sophia" (Folder 6)
      - Orders, mostly Sophia Garrison (Folder 7)
  - 1893
    - Clippings (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - Diplomatic, includes P. Dimitrov, Bulgarian Diplomatic Agent in Constantinople, B. Goranov, Bulgarian Diplomatic Agent in Belgrade and Teodorov, Bulgarian Diplomatic Agent in Bucharest (Folder 9)
      - Incoming (Folder 10)
      - Marie-Louise (Folder 11)
      - Stambolov, Stefan (Folder 12)
      - Summaries of official correspondence (Folder 13-14)
      - Summaries of official correspondence (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Printed matter (Folder 2)
    - Public works (Folder 3)
  - 1894
    - Bulletin (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Stambolov, Stefan (Folder 6)
      - Summaries of official correspondence (Folder 7)
    - Orders (Folder 8)
  - 1895
    - Clippings (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Grekov, L. E. (Folder 11)
      - Incoming (Folder 12)
      - Outgoing (Folder 13)
      - Stoilov, C. (Folder 14)
    - Daily reports (Folder 15-17)
  - 1896
    - Clippings (Folder 18)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 19)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 20)
      - Incoming (Folder 21)
      - Outgoing (Folder 22)
      - Stoilov, C. (Folder 23)
    - Military matters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Orders (Folder 2)
    - Program, address to deputies and other miscellaneous material re opening of National Assembly (Folder 3)
    - "Relation du voyage de S. A. R. Monseigneur le Prince de Bulgarie, Constantinople" (Folder 4)
    - "Unterredung mit Sr. Koniglichen Hoheit dem Fursten Ferdinand v. Bulgarien" (Folder 5)
  - 1897
    - Clippings (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Incoming (Folder 8)
    - Clippings (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 11)
      - Incoming (Folder 12)
      - Marie (Folder 13)
      - Outgoing (Folder 14)
      - Stoilov, C. (Folder 15)
    - Daily reports (Folder 16)
    - Financial matters (Folder 17)
    - Military and naval matters, including "Nadezhda" incident (Folder 18)
    - Minutes of meeting, National Assembly, Nov. 9, 1898 (Folder 19)
  - 1899
    - Clippings (Folder 20)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 21)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 22)
      - Grekov, D. (Folder 23-24)
      - Incoming (Folder 25)
      - Outgoing (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Stoilov, C. (Folder 2)
    - Daily reports (Folder 3)
    - Financial matters (Folder 4)
  - 1900
    - Clippings (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 7)
      - Incoming (Folder 8)
      - Outgoing (Folder 9)
    - Daily reports (Folder 10-14)
    - Map, "Proekt zheleznoi dorogi Varna-Antivari" (Folder 15)
    - Military matters (Folder 16)
  - 1901
    - Clippings (Folder 17)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 18)
      - Incoming (Folder 19)
      - Outgoing (Folder 20)
    - Daily reports (Folder 21-22)
    - Daily reports (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Macedonian question (Folder 4)
    - Military matters (Folder 5)
    - Printed matter
      - Journals, including, Pravoslavnyi Vostok, Oct. 1901 (Folder 6)
      - Wall poster, "Prestona Beseda...Aleksandar I..." (Folder 7)
  - 1902
    - Clippings (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Dobrovich, S. and "Kantseliariia na Negovo Tsrsko Visochestvo kniaz'te" (Folder 10)
      - Incoming (Folder 11-12)
      - Outgoing, includes drafts of official addresses (Folder 13)
    - Daily reports (Folder 14-15)
    - Military matters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 2)
    - Printed matter
      - General, including "Derzhavin Vestnik" (Folder 3)
      - "Ego Siiatel'stvu Grafu V.N. Lamzdorfu ot Makedonsko-Adrianopol'skoi Emigratsii" (Folder 4)
    - Reports (Folder 5)
    - Stanchov, diaries and other writings (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 7)
    - Clippings (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 10)
      - Edward VII, King of Great Britain (Folder 11)
      - Incoming (Folder 12-15)
      - Incoming (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
      - Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia (Folder 6)
      - Outgoing (Folder 7)
      - William II, German Emperor (Folder 8)
    - Daily reports (Folder 9)
    - Daily reports (Box 13, Folder 1-8)
    - Franz-Josef, audience with (Folder 9)
    - Maps (Folder 10)
    - Military matters (Folder 11)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - General, including material regarding the Macedonian crisis (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
      - Draft of agreement between Bulgaria and Serbia (Folder 7)
      - "Notice", reports, signed Veruazza (?) (Folder 8)
    - Notes (Folder 9)
    - Printed matter
      - General (Folder 10)
      - "Manifest' k'm' b'lgarskiia narod'" (Folder 11)
    - "Projet d'un canal maritime du Lac de Devno a la mer", blueprint (Folder 12)
    - "Zakonoproekt za Gorite," report, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, includes calling cards, printed menus, invitations (Folder 14)
  - 1904
    - Alexandrine of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha, personal papers, including will (Folder 15)
    - Clippings (Folder 16)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha, includes other, miscellaneous family correspondence (Folder 2)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 3)
      - Incoming, includes official reports (Folder 4-9)
      - Incoming, includes official reports (Box 16, Folder 1-10)
      - Outgoing (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Daily reports (Folder 2-10)
    - Daily reports (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - Ministry of Agriculture and Commerce, draft project (Folder 4)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - Correspondence (Folder 5-10)
      - "Declaration de la Sublime Porte aux ambassadeur d'Autriche-Hongrie et de Russie" (Folder 11)
      - Reports
        - Macedonian situation, reports on, in German (Folder 12)
        - "Notice", signed Veruazza (Folder 13)
        - St. Petersburg, Russia, reports from (Folder 14)
      - Serbia, drafts of agreements between Bulgaria and Serbia, includes miscellaneous related material (Folder 15)
    - Ministry of War, including miscellaneous military matters
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Maps (Folder 17)
      - Reports
        - Kuropatkin, Gen. A., "Vypiski iz dnevnika...za vremia prebyvaniia ego v Bolgarii v Sentiabre 1902 goda", 1902 (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Tsokov, D., re Russo-Japanese War (Folder 2)
        - Turkish military, in French (Folder 3)
    - Printed matter (Folder 4)
  - 1905
    - Clippings (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 7)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 8)
      - Incoming (Folder 9-14)
      - Outgoing (Folder 15)
      - "Visitenliste", miscellaneous material re European visits, 1905 (Folder 16)
    - Daily reports (Folder 17)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, correspondence (Folder 18)
  - 1906
    - Brief history of Ferdinand's reign, handwritten draft (Folder 19)
    - Clippings (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha, includes holograph letter from Franz-Josef, Emperor of Austria (Folder 3)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 4)
      - Duncan, Isadora (Folder 5)
      - Incoming (Folder 6-9)
      - Outgoing (Folder 10)
    - Military matters (Folder 11)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, notes (Folder 13)
  - 1907
    - Address, "Gospoda Narodny Diputaty" (Folder 14)
    - Clippings (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 16-17)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Incoming (Folder 2-11)
      - Incoming (Box 22, Folder 1-8)
      - Outgoing (Folder 9-10)
    - Dernburg, B., "Koloniale Erziehung" (Folder 11)
    - Military and security matters (Folder 12)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - General (Folder 13)
      - "Discours du Ministre des Affaires Etrangeres", typescript (Folder 14)
      - Reports re situation in Austro-Hungary, typescript (Folder 15)
    - Sermon, funeral of Clementine, Princess of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Folder 16)
    - "Zakon za Lov" (Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, financial papers (Folder 18)
  - 1908
    - Clippings (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 4-6)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 7)
      - Incoming (Box 24, Folder 1-11)
      - Incoming (Box 25, Folder 1-7)
      - Outgoing, including drafts of speeches (Folder 8)
    - Daily reports (Folder 9)
    - List of personnel employed in royal palace (Folder 10)
    - Marriage of Ferdinand and Princess Eleonore Reuss (Folder 11)
    - Military matters
      - Draft of mutual defense agreement between Bulgaria and Turkey, includes Bulgarian and Turkish texts, typescript (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Plans for military manoeuvres, Austro-Hungarian army (Folder 2)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - Correspondence (Folder 3)
      - Reports from Paris, by N. Stanchov (Folder 4)
    - "Programa za t"rzhestvenoto otkrivane...XIV...Narodno S"branie", printed copy (Folder 5)
    - Program, reception in Budapest, Sept. 1908, handwritten and printed material (Folder 6)
    - Protocol, Council of Ministers, Feb. 4 (Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, notes (Folder 8-9)
  - 1909
    - Clippings and handwritten excerpts from press, including royal visit to Serbia (Folder 10)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 12)
      - Eleonore, Princess (Folder 13)
      - Incoming (Folder 14)
      - Incoming (Box 27, Folder 1-11)
      - Incoming (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
      - Outgoing, including drafts of speeches (Folder 3)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Sofia, Haridjie, Vienna, London (Folder 5)
      - Reports, Stanchov, N. (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, announcements (Folder 7)
  - 1910
    - Clippings (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 9-10)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Eleonore (Folder 2)
      - Incoming (Folder 3-11)
      - Outgoing, including drafts of speeches (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "Doklad do Negovo Velichestvo Tsaria" and "Zakonoproekt za veroizpovedaniiata v Tsarstvo Belgariia", typescript (Folder 2)
    - Military matters (Folder 3)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Belgarska Tsarska Legatsiia, Belgrad, reports and correspondence (Folder 5)
      - Belgarsko Generalno Konsulstvo v Solune, correspondence and reports (Folder 6)
    - State visits
      - France (Folder 7)
      - Russia (Folder 8)
      - Turkey (Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, announcements (Folder 10-11)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, announcements (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - 1911
    - Clippings (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 4)
      - Eleonore (Folder 5)
      - Incoming (Folder 6-10)
      - Incoming (Box 32, Folder 1-5)
      - Outgoing (Folder 6)
    - Military matters, including reports on Turkish and Serbian armies (Folder 7)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, external affairs (Folder 8)
    - "Ploshchad' 'Sv. Aleksandr" Nevskii'", Sophia (Folder 9)
    - Railroad, Tyrnovo (Folder 10)
    - Reports
      - Education, Princes Boris and Kiril, typescript (Folder 11)
      - Government ministries: railroad, mail, education (Folder 12)
      - Paprikov, Gen. S., St. Petersburg (Folder 13)
      - Pichon, Lieut. J.
        - "Un itineraire en Serbie", typescript (Folder 14)
        - "Introduction et chapitre premier. Peuples des Balkans. Leurs groupements." Typescript (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, menus, announcements (Folder 2)
  - 1912
    - Clippings and press summaries (Folder 3-5)
    - Correspondence
      - Anonymous, addressed to Ferdinand (Folder 6)
      - Armenian Patriarchate (Folder 7)
      - Bulgarian Ambassadors and Ministers Plenipotentiary
        - Athens (Folder 8)
        - Belgrade (Folder 9-10)
        - Berlin (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Bucharest (Folder 2)
        - Cetinje (Folder 3)
        - Constantinople (Folder 4)
        - London (Folder 5)
        - Rome (Folder 6)
        - Solun (Folder 7)
        - St. Petersburg (Folder 8)
        - Vienna (Folder 9)
      - Bulgarian Army, Chief of Staff (Folder 10)
      - Bulgarian Exarch in Constantinople, IOsif I (Folder 11)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 12)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Eleonore (Folder 2)
      - Geshov, E. (Folder 3)
      - Incoming (Folder 4-11)
      - Incoming (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
      - Marie, Queen of Rumania to Eleonore, Queen of Bulgaria (Folder 5)
      - Minister of War (Folder 6-7)
      - Outgoing (Folder 8-10)
      - Outgoing (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
      - Savvov, General (Folder 6)
      - Telegrams
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Encoded, to S. Dobrovich (Folder 8)
    - Law (Folder 9)
    - Military matters
      - "Biuletin", reports re military situation, typescript (Folder 10)
      - Lists of officers presented with order "Za khrabrost'", typescript (Folder 11)
      - Maps indicating disposition of troops (Folder 12)
      - Treaties, "Traite d'Alliance defensive entre la Bulgarie et la Grece", handwritten and "Convention Militaire", typescript (Folder 13)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Conference de Saint-James, lists of delegates and protocols (Folder 15)
      - Report, "Les frontieres de l'Albanie d'apres les actes internationaux", typescript (Folder 16)
    - Railroads, "Izlozhenie na motivite k"m" zakonoproekta za razshirenie mrezhatana Belgarskite d"rzhavni zheleznitsi", address to national representatives, printed copy. Also includes map, 1911 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 2)
      - From St. Petersburg (Folder 3)
    - Speeches (Folder 4)
    - State visits
      - Germany (Folder 5)
      - Vienna (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, itineraries, announcements (Folder 7-8)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Folder 9-10)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Box 39, Folder 1-6)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Box 41, Folder 1-7)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Box 42, Folder 1-8)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Box 43, Folder 1-6)
  - 1912-13, Dossier de la Guerre (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - 1913
    - Clippings and summaries of newspaper articles (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 3-6)
      - General (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
      - Boris of Tyrnovo (Folder 5)
      - Bulgarian Ambassadors and Ministers Plenipotentiary
        - Belgrade (Folder 6)
        - Berlin (Folder 7)
        - Constantinople (Folder 8)
        - Paris (Folder 9)
        - Rome (Bulgarian Legation) (Folder 10)
        - St. Petersburg (Bulgarian Legation) (Folder 11)
      - Dimitriev, Gen. R. (Folder 12)
      - Diplomatic (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Dobrovich, S. (Folder 2-3)
      - Eleonore (Folder 4)
      - Incoming (Folder 5-8)
      - Incoming (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Kovachev, Gen. (Folder 2)
      - Military Attache, Vienna and Berlin (Folder 3)
      - Outgoing (Folder 4)
      - Paprikov, Gen. S. (Folder 5)
    - Military matters
      - General (Folder 6)
      - "Biuletin", reports re military situation, typescript (Folder 7)
      - List of officers presented with order "Za khrabrost'" (Folder 8)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Treaty between Serbia and Greece, French, typescript (Folder 10)
    - Police reports (Folder 11)
    - Reports
      - Bulgarian nationals in Greece (Folder 12)
      - "Promemoria uber die Lage Bulgariens, Anfangs, Dezember 1913", typescript (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, includes invitations, announcements (Folder 14-15)
  - 1914
    - Bulgaria
      - Foreign relations
        - General (Folder 16)
        - Germany (Folder 17)
      - Military affairs (Folder 18)
    - Clippings (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 2-5)
      - General (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
      - American Consular Service, Sofia (Folder 3)
      - Bainbridge, Oliver (Folder 4)
      - Bengliev, Mikhail (Folder 5)
      - Bulgarian Consulate in Budapest (Folder 6)
      - Bulgarian Consulate General in Odrin (Folder 7)
      - Bulgarian Consulate General in Valona (Albania) (Folder 8)
      - Bulgarian Legation in Athens (Folder 9)
      - Bulgarian Legation in Belgrade (Folder 10)
      - Bulgarian Legation in Berlin (Folder 11)
      - Bulgarian Legation in Bucharest (Folder 12)
      - Bulgarian Legation in London (Folder 13)
      - Bulgarian Legation in St. Petersburg (Folder 14)
      - Bulgarian Legation in Vienna (Folder 15)
      - Bulgarian military attaches abroad (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
      - Bulgarian Minister in Paris (Folder 4)
      - Bulgarian Minister in Rome (Folder 5)
      - Carol, King of Romania (Folder 6)
      - Congratulatory telegrams (Folder 7)
      - Director of Postal, Telegraph and Telephone Services (Folder 8)
      - Fichev, General (Folder 9)
      - Ionkov-Vladikin (Folder 10)
      - Iosif, Ekzarkh (Folder 11)
      - Karovelova, G. (Folder 12)
      - Mefodii, Mitropolit (Folder 13)
      - Nachalnik na Shchaba na Armiiata (Folder 14)
      - Nenkov, Dr. (Folder 15)
      - O'Mahony, Pierce (Folder 16)
      - Radoslavov, V. (Folder 17)
      - Radoslavov, V. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Tsankov, Father Stefan (Folder 2)
      - Vratchansko Okrzhzhko Upravlenie (Folder 3)
    - Grecow, G., report from Paris (Folder 4)
    - Jews (Folder 5)
    - Laxa, Colonel, reports (Folder 6)
    - Maps (Folder 7)
    - Police reports (Folder 8)
    - Rosenthal, M., reports (Folder 9)
    - Speeches (Folder 10)
    - Stanchov, Colonel, reports (Folder 11)
    - Toshev, General, reports (Folder 12)